Preliminary Inventory to the William Yandell Elliott papers
Hoover Institution Archives
William Yandell Elliott papers
1925-1974
77091
Hoover Institution Archives
197 manuscript boxes (80.0 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, speeches, research notes, clippings, and printed matter relating to American national security and defense, American politics and foreign relations, American military-industrial relations, and American national labor policy.
Elliott, William Yandell, 1896-
Access
Collection open for research.
Use copies of all sound recordings in this collection are available. For access to any video recordings or motion picture film in this collection, please contact the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
American political scientist; staff director, House Select Committee on Foreign Affairs, 1947-1949; member, planning board, National Security Council, 1953-1957; consultant to the secretary of state, 1958-1970.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1977, with increments received in 1988 and 1997.
United States. Congress.; United States. Dept. of State.; United States. National Security Council.; Great Britain--Politics and government.; Great Britain.; International economic relations.; Labor movement--United States.; United States--Armed Forces.; United States--Defenses.; United States--Economic conditions.; United States--Foreign relations--1945-1989.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Politics and government--1945-1989.; United States--Politics and government.
- Conference on The Marriage of Political Philosophy and Practice in Public Affairs - in honor of Professor Elliott, Harvard Summer School, July 22-24, 1963 (Box 1)
- Harvard University graduation
- Committee on Prizes
- Manuscript
- Harvard Summer School Conference for WYE, 1963
- Papers, notes (old)
- WYE's retirement letters
- Harvard University (Box 2)
  - International Affairs Center
  - Associated Harvard clubs
  - Harvard Club of NY City
  - Faculty Club
  - Defense Studies Program
  - British Defense Policy Seminar, 1954
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences (Bundy)
  - International Seminar, 1951-1959
  - Governmental Affairs Institute (Foreign Visitors)
  - GSPA curriculum
  - Graduate School of Public Administration
- Harvard activities (Box 3)
- Correspondence, 1950-1956
- Harvard University
  - Committee on International and Regional Studies
  - Middle East Studies, 1952
  - Committee on Educational Policy
- Barry Bingham's Committee on Private Organizations and Public Speeches (LaGuardia's Off.), 1941
- Russia - American Committee for Liberation on Russia, H. Sargeant
- The Harvard Crimson
- Memoranda of Conferences With Representative of Office of Price Administration Relating to Review of O.P.A. Survey Data and Field Notes Made During This Review Underwear Institute, New York, New York, October 23, 1946
- Maps - foreign trade route areas
- Great Britain - Central Executive Government and War Cabinet (Box 4)
- Economic Warfare - Memos, 1959
- Constitutional Reform
- Balfour and Wilson, 1931
- Introduction - The Nature of American Government
- Cultural Heritage of the US
- The President's Role in Administrative Management, 1942
- Principia College Conference, - Government and General Welfare, 1950
- Education, Bricks and Mortar - Harvard Buildings and Their Contribution to the Advancement of Learning, 1949 (Box 5)
- National Security, 1950
- Conference of National Organizations, 1967-1969
- American University
  - Farm outings for students
  - Dissertation Committees
  - Courses and texts
  - Examinations
  - Task Force on Principles and Objectives
- Writings by WYE
- American University (Box 6)
  - Faculty, Memos to and from
- Correspondence, 1951-1959
- ETV Conference (Harvard), 1956
- Foundation for Religious Action in the Social and Civil Order
- Herter, Christian
- Miscellany (Box 7)
- Committee on Foreign Aid (Box 8)
  - Letters and dispatches, 1947
  - Germany
  - Poland
- U.S. House of Representatives. First Foreign Aid Res., 173
- Displaced Persons, Fulton Sub-Committee
- American University
  - Faculty meetings
  - Library
  - Reading lists
  - Provost
  - Exams
- Harvard University exams
- Foreign Relief Bill - $350,000,000 (C.A.N.)
- Frances Bolton Sub-Committee of Foreign Affairs
- Kiwanis International
- Manske, Robert F., Ph.D. candidate
- Committee on Public Administration Cases
- Harvard University, Center for International Affairs
- Foreign Affairs Hearing material
- Miscellany (Box 9)
- Woodrow Wilson study group (Box 10)
- Foreign Policy Research Institute, 1955
- Seminar papers
- American University
  - Advisory Council
  - I-R Sub-Faculty
- Millikan, Max, "The Political Case for Economic Development Aid,", n.d. (Box 11)
- International Educational and Cultural Activities for the Books I, III, IV, V, 1960s
- Government Seminar 285, 1956-1961
- Miscellany (Box 12-13)
- American University (Box 14)
  - CUE
    - Art
    - Anthropology
    - AAUP Committee Z
    - Biology
    - Chemistry
    - CTA
    - Economics
    - History
    - Philosophy and Religion
    - SON
    - WCL
- Books loaned to students
- Correspondence
  - B, 1963-1969
  - Barnett, Frank, 1965-1968
- American Bar Association, Liebman
- Reprint
- Carnegie Endowment
- Miscellany (Box 15-17)
- Canadian trip, Carleton University, December 1968 (Box 18)
- Negro Taxi Drivers Association
- Summer School, 1953
- Faculty Effort Report
- Project Vision
- "The False Dilemma of Bertrand Russell," by WYE, June 2, 1960
- Institute for American Strategy (Fisher)
- Conference of National Organizations meeting, May 7-8, 1969
- Correspondence
- Lectures
- "Executive - Congressional Relations in the Formulation and Control of United States Foreign Policy As They Concern the Department of State," by WYE, November 1, 1950
- Technical Assistance Subcommittee
- Notes on New British Empire
- Miscellany (Box 19-20)
- Atlantic Institute papers (various authors) (Box 21)
- Business Council, 1962-1966
- National Home Library Association
- Valley Forge Freedom Foundation
- FTC in camera treatment
- Dart Drug Corporation
- Principia College Conferences, 1964-1966 (Box 22)
- National Home Library Foundation, accountant reports, 1965-1966
- Rockefeller Foundation materials
- Correspondence, "C" names
- Principia College Conferences, 1961, 1965, 1968 (Box 23)
- Department of State memos, 1958-1959
- Underdeveloped countries, African studies by John Montgomery
- Underdeveloped countries, leadership, Kenneth Young, 1957
- Books ordered through, 1965
- Eastern Baptist College lectures, 1964
- Schools, Colleges, etc. (Box 24)
- Denver University
- Duke University
- Radcliffe University
- University of Florida
- University of South Carolina
- Vanderbilt University
- Waterloo University
- Webb School
- NATO - Atlantic Community documents
- American Assembly, 1959-1960
- Papers by students (Box 25)
- Miscellany (Box 26)
- Smithies' Report On Visit to Europe, 1950 (Box 27)
- Kissinger, Henry, memos re: U.S. strategy, 1951
- Far Eastern policy, 1950-1951
- U.S. labor relations
- Russia
- Review: Baruch, 1951
- The Progressive, Rubin
- Roundtable for Freedom, 1950
- "Congress and Foreign Policy," by WYE, April 1949
- American Political Science Association, December 1949
- MacLeish, Archibald, "The Conquest of America," reprint, Atlantic Monthly, August 1949
- "Our Stake in Arming Europe," by WYE, May 18, 1949
- "Private, Secondary, College Education and Free Institutions in the U.S.," by WYE, May 1949
- "Treason to Freedom,", April 28, 1949
- Debate on Far East Policy, Chicago, 1951
- McMahon and Tydings' proposals, February 1950
- "Prospects For Personal Freedom...," Hoskins, Annals, 1949
- Interstate Trade Papers
- Stockpiling
- "A Time For Peace," Virginia Quarterly Review
- WYE on Russia
- Memorandum on the British Cabinet Office (Box 28)
- National Foreign Trade Council, 1944
- "Political Determinants of Economic Policies"
- Imperial Conference, proceedings, London, 1921
- "Howard Case," letters
- American Political Science Association - Need for Constitutional reform, December 1946
- Atlantic Pact, 1949
- Russia, memoranda
- U.S. government and business, memos, 1947
- Cabinet-Secretariat
- British Ministry of Supply
- Trade, memos, 1946
- Business attitude on full employment and labor policy, 1947
- Naval War College speeches, 1952-1960 (Box 29)
- Richmond speech, November 8, 1951
- Speeches and writings by WYE
- Aptitude Associates, 1955
- Town Meeting of the Air, November 28, 1946 (Box 30)
- Mobilization Planning for National Security, 1950-1960
- Korean War, letter to Nitze, 1950
- "Objectives and Vital Interests of the U.S.," speech, War College, July 12, 1960
- Epstein, Julius, "The Case Against Vera Micheles Dean of the Foreign Policy Association,", 1947
- American Association of University Women, 1953-1955
- Annapolis speeches
- Industrial College of Armed Forces speeches, 1951, 1954
- Woodrow Wilson Foundation, May 22, 1951
- Speeches by WYE
- Buffalo speech, August 27, 1952
- Correspondence, "S-W" names, 1950
- Miscellany (Box 31)
- Harvard University (Box 32)
  - Libraries
  - Memorial Church
  - Minutes on life of Norris B. Lambie
  - Pakistan report
  - Publication funds
  - Retirement
  - Russian Research Center
  - Social activities
  - University Press
- AID (Box 33)
- American Academy of Arts and Sciences
- American Academy of Political and Social Science
- American Association for Advancement of Science
- American Political Science Association
- American Society for Political and Legal Philosophy
- Brookings Institution
- Buck, Solon, correspondence, 1947
- Business Advisory Council
- Papers, notes, speeches
- Students' papers (Box 34)
- A Report on National Labor Policy
- Harvard University
  - Student clubs
  - United Nations Council
  - Summer School
- Japanese trade
- Motion Picture Bill
- Colonialism
- Miscellany
- Correspondence - Western Political Heritage (Box 35)
- Poetry mss.
- Book - Teacher training
- Book - Praeger, Harvard Conference, 1960
- Harvard Summer School, 1964-1966
- National Security Policy, 1958 (Box 36)
- Tutorial - General information
- A Report on National Labor Policy (Box 37)
- Seminar 204
- Harvard Summer School
- Miscellany (Box 38)
- Harvard Conference, Near-Middle Eastern Affairs, 1946 (Box 39)
- National Security Policy, 1958
- Harvard Summer School, 1959-1962
- "President's Role in Administrative Management," by W. Y. Elliott (Box 40)
- National Security Policy, 1958
- International Educational and Cultural Activities for the at Harvard University, 1960s
- Harvard Summer School, 1948-1950
- Miscellany (Box 41-43)
- "The Strategy of American Foreign Policy," lecture-discussion series conducted by W. Y. Elliott, 1947 (Box 44)
- Students' papers
- International Education and Cultural Activities for the, 1960s
- Harvard Defense Policy Seminar, 1956-1957 (Box 45)
- Miscellany
- Miscellany (Box 46)
- Harvard Defense Policy Seminar, 1956-1957 (Box 47)
- Harvard University Center for International Affairs, 1961-1962
- Harvard Defense Policy Seminar, 1955-1957 (Box 48)
- Miscellany (Box 49-53)
- Goldwater (Box 54)
- Foreign Affairs Committee and ECA
- Foreign Service Educational Foundation
- Foreign Service Institute, Department of State, lectures
- Freedom Commission Act
- Galant, Henry
- A.U. - Dean Griffith, S.I.S.
- European Recovery Program
- Foreign Affairs Committee and ERP
- European reconstruction, 1947
- E
- Fainsod, Merle, "The Komsomols"
- Committee on Foreign Affairs
- Committee on International Relations, Notre Dame
- Confluence
- Occupied Areas: Politico-Military Organization (Box 55)
- Oxonian and Oxford
- O
- N
- Hans Kohn, 7 March 1955
- William Y. Elliott, 28 March 1955
- Henry Kissinger, 21 March 1955
- William Y. Elliott, 7 February 1955
  Scope and Contents note
  A talk by Elliott at a seminar, "Contemporary Political Theory," recorded as both sound recordings and a transcript. The transcript starts approximately 4 minutes into the speech.
  Access
  Sound recordings use copy reference number: 77091_a_0012740
- McMahon
- Frank Nash
- William Y. Elliott, 28 March 1955
- W. Y. Elliott and H. Kissinger, 9 March 1953
- Jacob Taubes, 16 February 1953
- W. Y. Elliott, 9 February 1953
- Muhar, P. S. (Box 56)
- Murray, John C., Rev.
- M
- Nuclear industrial uses
- Niemeyer, 1956
- Council on Foreign Relations
- Defense and National Security
- Council on Religion and International Affairs
- Cuba
- Daedalus
- D.C. Political Science Association, speech
- Draper Committee
- De Grozia, Sebastian
- Disarmament - Survival, statements by B. Russell and J. C. Murray
- Dorrill, Wm.
- Dewey, Thomas E., personal record
- Economic Club of Chicago
- Canadian-American relations
- Catlin's paper - "Politics and Values" (Box 57)
- Catlin, George
- Civil Defense
- Clippings
- CED Labor Study Group
- Cold War
- Committee for Economic Development
- Coleman, James S.
- National Security Council
- Nanes, Allen
- National Academy of Economic and Political Science, 1955-1956
- The New Leader
- Mountain, Maurice J. (Committee on Government Operations)
- Peace Corps
- P
- Pauker, Guy
- Principia, 1948-1950
- Production
- Publications, general (Box 58)
- Q
- PLO 480
- Park, Sei Young
- Parker, Oriana Joy
- Patterson, Robert P., Mrs.
- Princeton University Conference, March 1959
- Postwar economic policy and planning
- Presidential inability
- Presses and publishers
- Praeger Publishing Co.
- U
- UNESCO (Box 59)
- United Fund
- Exhibits to report on U.S. Commercial Co.
- World Brotherhood
- XYZ
- Zack, Arnold
- Miscellany
- Von Weizsaecker, Carl F. (Box 60)
- Wilson, Charles E.
- V
- W
- Voegelin, Eric
- Taft Institute
- Taylor, David
- Triska, Jan
- T
- Trainor, William (Box 61)
- Scott, Andrew
- Sihler, William
- Somers, H. M.
- Smith, William Y., Major
- Spanier, John
- Spiro, Herbert
- Stanley, Timothy
- Stark, Richard
- S, 1950-1963
- Rothman, Stanley
- Ripley, Randall
- Rozek, Edward J.
- R
- Rhodes scholars (Box 62)
- Pugwash (Rostow), 1961
- Raven Society
- Republican Committee on Program and Progress
- Resiky-Dubnic article
- Richmond, University of
- Rieff, Philip
- Rielly, John
- Roach, James
- Rock, Vincent
- Rosecrance, Richard
- American Strategy and Strength (Task Force report)
- Army Ordnance School, Aberdeen, MD, May 5, 1961
- Judge Advocate General, Charlottesville, VA, October 27
- McGill Conference, November 21, 1961
- General Electric, December 1961
- Marquette University, March 8, 1961
- National Association of Mutual Savings Banks
- Army War College, Carlisle Barracks, Elliott speech, 1961 (Box 63)
- Hollins College Southern Humanities Conference, March 19, 1960
- Gunnery School speech, October 17, 1959
- Navy speeches, 1958
- World Affairs Council, 1960
- Ottawa speech for President, 1958
- Army War College (Carlisle Barracks) speeches, 1957-1960
- Speeches and writings, 1955-1957
- "The Strategy of American Foreign Economic Policy," School of Advanced International Studies, 1946 (Box 64)
- Vanderbilt University lectures, 1964
- Notre Dame University lectures, 1964
- National Association of Manufac. Clergy - Industrial
- Miscellany
- Vanderbilt University reunion, June 6, 1964 (Box 65)
- Principia College Conference, April 7-10, 1965
- Principia College Conference, April 1964
- Vanderbilt lectures, June 15, 1964
- Vanderbilt lectures, pre-, 1964
- Conference of National Organizations, Miami Beach, November 5, 1964
- Vanderbilt, July 29, 1965
- Vanderbilt Teacher Training Inst., July 29, 1964
- Speeches and writings
- Speeches, 1964-1965 (Box 66)
- Book reviews by WYE
- Speeches, 1959-1963
- Worcester Industrial Council and YMCA, 1962
- West Point speeches, 1962-
- Eastern Baptist College, 1964
- Grove City College, November 1963
- Speeches and lectures, 1963
- Desert Sun School commencement, 1964
- American Management Association, Industrial Preparedness Conference, NYC, 1962
- National War College speech, 1963
- Miscellany
- National War College lectures, 1957-1962 (Box 67)
- Webb School, Bell Buckle, Tenn., address, 1961
- Air War College, Alabama, 1961
- Grove City College lectures, November 1963
- Eastern Baptist College lectures, February 1964
- Air Force Academy speeches, 1962-
- Trinity College, April 8, 1962
- "Cultural Heritage of the U.S."
- Gov. Seminar 204, Summer 1959
- Gov. Seminar 204, Spring 1959
- W. Y. Elliott, 26 September and 3 October 1955
- Amory, Robert, 4 October 1954 (Box 68)
- Carroll, Jacob and Westerfield, 7 November 1955
- Gov. Seminar 204, Spring 1960
- Coolidge, Charles, 1 December 1952
- Finletter, Secretary
- Wilcox
- Hancock
- Ingram, George
- Kuhn, Ferdinand
- Neaverson - shipping papers
- Eckstein, Harry, 29 March 1954
- Kissinger, Henry -, March 8, 1954
- Elliott, W. Y., March 1, 1954
- Elliott, W. Y., 15 February 1954 (Box 69)
- Elliott, W. Y., 8 February 1954
- Lin, Paul T.K.
- Malkin, Peter Lawrence
- Sallager, Frederick
- Gov. Seminar 284, Spring 1963
- Gov. Seminar 284, 1962
- Gov. Seminar 284, Feb. 12, 1962
- Gov. Seminar 284, April 23, 1962
- Gov. Seminar 284, Coombs memo
- Schumpeter, Elizabeth, Japan and Manchuria
- Research topics
- Cutler, Robert, 31 October 1955 (Box 70)
- McMahon, 5 October 1953
- Bissell, Richard, October 26, 1953
- Healey, Denis, 19 October 1953
- Marshall, C. B., 2 November 1953
- Bowie, Robert, 9 November 1953
- Nash, Frank and Charles Coolidge, 16 November 1953
- Boonesteel, General, 25 October 1954
- Heeney, Arnold D. P., 17 October 1955
- Bonesteel, General, 14 November 1955
- Tutorial papers
- Tutorial student lists
- Gov. Seminar 204, 1957-1963
- Marshall, C. B., 11 October 1954 (Box 71)
- Reid, Ralph, 1 November 1954
- RUSK, 8 November 1954
- Campbell, John, 10 October 1955
- Government Seminar 285, 1949, 1951
- Government Seminar 204, 1957-1958
- University of Nigeria Smuckler report (Box 72)
- Gov. Seminar 284
- Hale, Robert
- Harvey, Bart
- Herrenschmidt, Jean Roger
- Hough, Jerry Fincher
- References, F-P, 1946-1952
- Harvard recommendations, 1962-1963
- Harvard Center for International Affairs, 1962-1963
- Scott, Andrew M. (Box 73)
- Shoesmith, Thomas P.
- Sindler, Allan P.
- Steinberg, David J.
- Wahlke, John C.
- Westerfield, Holt Bradford
- Wheeler, Jean H.
- Harvard Government Department
- Government Seminar 285, 1949-1958
- Carroll, Holbert N. (Box 74)
- Government Seminar 285
- Harvard recommendations, A-L, 1954-1962
- References, R-Z, 1940-1952
- Government Seminar 285 (Box 75)
- Government Department (Box 76)
- Government lists
- Government Department graduate student lists
- Government la
- Miscellany
- Government la (Box 77)
- Montgomery reply to ICA Task Force
- Government 110
- Government 154 and 156
- Buckley, Wm. F.
- B
- Correspondence, A-Z
- Conant, James
- Cook, Thomas
- Crank letters and jokes
- Crick, Bernard
- C
- Cuthbertson, Gilbert
- D
- Government Department (Box 78)
- Gov. 1a
- Gov. 1b
- Government Sla (Box 79)
- Gov. 184
- Government 190
- Government 300
- Government 301
- Miscellany
- Gov. 1b (Box 80)
- Government Department
- Old Gov. bibliographies, courses
- Correspondence
- Elder Doctrine
- Elliott's Final Government Lecture at Harvard, Spring 1963 (Box 81)
- Miscellany (Box 82-85)
- Articles (Box 86)
- APSA, St. Louis, September 8-9, 1961
- Reid, Ralph, paper delivered at A.P.S.A., Chicago, September 10, 1954
- Marshall, C.B., paper developed at A.P.S.A., Chicago, September 10, 1954
- American Political Science Association, Chicago, 1954
- American Political Science Association, 1951-1955
- Communism - Strategy for Peace Conference, New York, 1960-1963
- Institute for American Strategy, Chicago, 1957-
- American Strategy and Strength, Republican Task Force Report, 1960 (Box 87)
- National Military-Industrial Conference, Chicago, April 1961
- Institute for American Strategy
- American Security Council
- American Bar Association
- Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1956-1959 (Box 88)
- "Moral Ingredient of Power," by WYE, March 1957
- Miscellany
- Rockefeller Brothers Fund (Box 89)
- Rockefeller Brothers Fund (Box 90)
- Miscellany
- Rockefeller Brothers Fund (Box 91)
- Rockefeller Foundation (Box 92)
- Woodrow Wilson Centennial
- Writings by WYE
- Cape Giradeaux lectures (Box 93)
- Addresses by WYE
- Huntington, Sam
- Hardin, Chas. H.
- Conferences, Councils
  - Department of State Conference on Cultural Relations at Harvard, 1960
- United States Chamber of Commerce, May 1962
- H
- F (Box 94)
- Fenno, Richard
- Ford, Joseph P.
- Friedrich, Carl J.
- G
- Glaser, William
- Hadwiger, Don
- Hammond, Paul Young
- Hanson and Herter
- Harvard University Zemurray Professorship
- Heineman, Mel
- Herter, Christian
- Holcombe's speech at Board of Overseers dinner, April 11, 1955
- Huff, Lee
- Hungarian revolt
- Hunt, Herold, Professor
- Department of State
  - Administrative matters
  - Publications
  - Dean Rusk
  - Correspondence (Box 95)
- United Nations
- Principia College conferences, 1951-1967
- Foreign Policy Research Institute (Box 96)
- Foundations
- Writings by WYE
- Foreign Policy Research Institute (Box 97)
- Old Dominion Foundation
- League of Nations World Peace Foundation
- Fund for International Freedom
- Carnegie Endowment for International Peace
- Ford Foundation (Jos. Slater)
- Foundations
- Fund for the Republic
- Foreign Policy Research Institute (Box 98)
  - Agenda for meetings
  - Staff conference reports
  - Staff papers
  - Miscellany
  - Correspondence (Box 99)
  - Staff papers
  - UN book
  - General (Box 100)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1964
  - Institute for Defense Analyses Study
  - Draper Committee
  - Expenses, vouchers, etc.
  - Membership operations reports
  - Propaganda activities, Fullbright memo and comments
  - Proposal to Rockefeller, 1958-1959
  - Special Projects Outlines, 1955-1959
- Communism (Box 101)
  - General
  - American University Inst.
  - East Carolina College
  - Education in Indiana
  - Education in miscellaneous states
  - Florida Department of Education
  - Teaching the nature of, in American schools
  - National Education Association, Project on Instruction (Box 102)
  - St. Louis University
  - University of Southern California
  - Vanderbilt Institute, 1962-1963
- Conferences (Box 103)
  - Convocation for University Pastors, July 18, 1963
  - Principia Conference, April 3-5, 1963
- Correspondence
  - Re: President Kennedy
  - Special Colonel Posvar
  - Muhas (India)
  - Conant, James B.
- Florida Governors Conference, 1963
- Parel, Anthony J., Rev.
- Steinberg, David J.
- Teacher Training
  - Communism
- Vanderbilt University, summer, 1963
  - Vanderbilt University Institute on Nature of Communism, summer 1962
- Communism (Box 104)
  - Bronxville, NY School (Richard Perdew)
  - Institute at South Carolina (Dr. Richard L. Walker)
  - Lilly Endowment, 1961-1963
  - Miscellany
- Education and World Affairs
- Vanderbilt University
- Miscellany (Box 105-107)
- Television clippings, articles, etc. (Box 108)
- Educational TV, 1956
- Monroe Bush, Project Vision
- Guy Pauker
- Departmental negotiations - general education
- Harvard Law Forum
- Miscellany
- Film and television correspondence (Box 109)
- Project Vision
- TV study - Old Dominion Foundation
- Old Dominion Foundation
- FCC Hearings
- Educational television (Box 110)
- Correspondence
  - Darden, Hutchinson, Newman - V.P.I. and Univ. of Va.
  - JCET TV
  - Quillian, William
- Television info sheets, articles, etc.
- National Association of Educational Broadcasters
- American Research Center in Egypt
- Air Force, 1951-1955
- WETA TV
- Central Intelligence Agency, 1949-1951
- WYE's TV book material